Power changes everything
The Current War is a drama, history film directed by Alfonso Gomez-Rejon.
Electricity titans Thomas Edison and George Westinghouse compete to create
a sustainable system and market it to the American people.
Thomas Edison, played by Benedict Cumberbatch.
George Westinghouse, played by Michael Shannon.
Nikola Tesla, played by Nicholas Hoult.
Marguerite Westinghouse, played by Katherine Waterston.
Samuel Insull, played by Tom Holland.
J.P. Morgan, played by Matthew Macfadyen.
The Current War is a 2017 historical drama film inspired by the 19th-century competition between Thomas Edison and George Westinghouse over
which electric power delivery system would be used in the United States (often referred to as the "war of the currents").
Directed by Alfonso Gomez-Rejon, written by Michael Mitnick, and executive produced by Martin Scorsese and Steven Zaillian, the film stars Benedict Cumberbatch as Edison, Michael Shannon
as Westinghouse, Nicholas Hoult as Nikola Tesla, and Tom Holland as Samuel Insull, alongside Katherine Waterston, Tuppence Middleton, Matthew Macfadyen and Damien Molony.
Announced in May 2012, Gomez-Rejon was confirmed in September 2015.
Cumberbatch, Shannon, and Hoult joined the cast by October
2016, and filming began in England that December.
The film premiered at the Toronto International
Film Festival on September 9, 2017.
Originally to be distributed by The Weinstein Company, the film was shelved and sold in
November 2017 following the sexual abuse allegations made against Harvey Weinstein.
It was eventually bought by Weinstein Company successor Lantern Entertainment,
which then sold domestic distribution rights to 101 Studios.
After discovering a final cut privilege clause in Scorsese's contract, Gomez-Rejon convinced him to allow for reshoots and to trim
ten minutes off the original version's runtime, resulting in the film that was eventually released into theaters.
The film was released in the United States on October 25, 2019.
The film received generally mixed reviews, with praise towards the cast's performances and
the intriguing story, but with criticism towards the overall execution.
The tone is emotional.